<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="RenderSceneData" inherits="Object" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Abstract render data object, holds scene data related to rendering a single frame of a viewport.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		Abstract scene data object, exists for the duration of rendering a single viewport. See also [RenderSceneDataRD], [RenderData], and [RenderDataRD].
		[b]Note:[/b] This is an internal rendering server object. Do not instantiate this class from a script.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="get_aspect" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the X:Y aspect ratio of camera projection used to render this frame.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_cam_projection" qualifiers="const" deprecated="Use [method RenderSceneData.get_transformed_projection_data] instead.">
			<return type="Projection" />
			<description>
				Returns the camera projection used to render this frame. This is a transformed projection and is only suitable for copying to the GPU.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return a combined projection.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_cam_transform" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="Transform3D" />
			<description>
				Returns the camera transform used to render this frame.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return a centered transform.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_far_plane_half_extents" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="Vector2" />
			<description>
				Returns the dimensions of the far clipping plane of the projection used to render this frame, divided by two.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return centered dimensions.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_pixels_per_meter" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="int" />
			<param index="0" name="for_pixel_width" type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns [param for_pixel_width] divided by the viewport's width measured in meters on the near plane, after this view's projection is applied.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return centered dimensions.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_transformed_projection_data" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="PackedFloat32Array" />
			<description>
				Returns the camera projection data used to render this frame. This is transformed projection data and is only suitable for copying to the GPU.
				To access the near and far distances, use [method get_z_near] and [method get_z_far].
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return combined projection data.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_uniform_buffer" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="RID" />
			<description>
				Return the [RID] of the uniform buffer containing the scene data as a UBO.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_view_count" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns the number of views being rendered.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_view_eye_offset" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="Vector3" />
			<param index="0" name="view" type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns the eye offset per view used to render this frame. This is the offset between our camera transform and the eye transform.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_view_projection" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="Projection" />
			<param index="0" name="view" type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns the view projection per view used to render this frame.
				[b]Note:[/b] If a single view is rendered, this returns the camera projection. If more than one view is rendered, this will return a projection for the given view including the eye offset.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_viewport_half_extents" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="Vector2" />
			<description>
				Returns the dimensions of the viewport plane used to render this frame, divided by two.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return centered dimensions.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_z_far" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the distance beyond which positions are clipped, used to render this frame.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return combined distance.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_z_near" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the distance before which positions are clipped, used to render this frame.
				[b]Note:[/b] If more than one view is rendered, this will return combined distance.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
